winamp.com 2013-05-08

# Privacy Policy - Winamp

Winamp is brought to you by Nullsoft, Inc. Nullsoft respects the privacy of our users. This Privacy Policy outlines how Nullsoft Winamp ("Winamp," "we," or "us") collects and uses information when you register for or use Winamp websites or when you download and use the Winamp player and other Winamp software, collectively "Services." 

The Winamp Privacy Policy does not apply to other companies' websites and services that you may access outside of the Winamp Services. The personal information collected or received by these other companies is subject to their own privacy policies.

Click the links below to learn about the following topics:

  * Collection of Your Winamp Information
  * How Your Winamp Information Is Used
  * Your Choices About your Winamp Information
  * Privacy Information for Specific Winamp Services
  * Cookies, Web Beacons, and Similar Technologies
  * Protecting Children
  * Security
  * How to Contact Us
  * Changes to this Policy

#### Collection of your Winamp Information

Your "Winamp Information" consists of personal information collected or received about you when you interact with Winamp Services. Depending on how you use the Winamp Services, your Winamp Information may include:

  * information you provide when you register for Winamp Services (such as name, e-mail addresses, birth date or gender);
  * information about how you use Winamp Services, including webpages you visit, software you download, or your responses to offerings and advertisements presented on Winamp websites;
  * information about the searches you perform through the Winamp Services and how you use the results of those searches;
  * transaction-related information (such as credit card or other preferred means of payment, billing or shipping information, or a history of products purchased through Winamp);
  * customer service information about you personally as a Winamp user or subscriber.

If you have not registered with Winamp, Winamp may collect the information above in a non-personally identifiable manner. Your Winamp Information may be supplemented with additional information from other companies.

Your Winamp Information may also include certain technical information gathered or received when you use Winamp Services. Some of the technical information that may be collected or received includes: the type of browser you are using (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using (e.g., Windows XP or Mac OS), CPU type (e.g. Pentium), your manner of connecting to the Internet (e.g., connection speed through narrowband or broadband access); Internet protocol address; information about the version of Winamp Services that you used prior to registering with the Network; other information about your geographic location; and the domain name of your Internet service provider.

Your Winamp Information may be collected and stored in the United States, even if you use Winamp Services in another country.

Winamp Services include integrated offerings and technologies provided by AOL Inc. to bring you certain optional services, such as the Winamp Orgler and sharing of Winamp Skins. These Winamp Services may use the Screen Name Service, or similar technologies, to authenticate you on Winamp and AOL Websites. Your use of the Screen Name Service and associated services account will be subject to the AOL [Terms of Service](http://legal.aol.com/TOS) and [Privacy Policy](http://privacy.aol.com/). You can learn more about other benefits of the Screen Name Service, including its ability to facilitate your use of websites outside of AOL, by visiting [Screen Name Service](http://my.screenname.aol.com/).

#### How Your Winamp Information is Used

Your Winamp Information is used:

  * to operate and improve the Services available through Winamp;
  * to personalize the content and advertisements provided to you;
  * to fulfill your requests for products, programs, and services;
  * to communicate with you and respond to your inquiries;
  * to conduct research about your use of Winamp; and
  * to help offer you other products, programs, or services that may be of interest.

Your Winamp information will not be shared with third parties unless it is necessary to fulfill a transaction you have requested, or in other circumstances in which you have been given notice and appropriate choices regarding this sharing.

We may use your Winamp Information to present offers to you on behalf of business partners and advertisers. These business partners and advertisers may receive aggregate data about groups of Winamp users, but do not receive information that personally identifies you.

If you use Winamp communication tools to disclose information about yourself publicly, other online users may have access to this public information (for example, in chat rooms or online message boards on Winamp websites).

Your Winamp Information and any other information we obtain about you, including the contents of your online communications, may be disclosed in response to legal process (for example, a court order, search warrant or subpoena); in other circumstances in which we believe Winamp is being used in the commission of a crime; when we have a good faith belief that there is an emergency that poses a threat to the safety of you or another person; or when necessary either to protect the rights or property of Nullsoft or its affiliated providers, or for us to render the service you have requested. 

We may use agents and contractors in order to help operate Winamp Services. If such agents and contractors have access to personally identifiable information, they are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy by, for example, not using the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing on our behalf.

#### Your Choices about Your Winamp Information

We offer you notice and appropriate choices about the use or sharing of your information, as described in this Privacy Policy. Specifically, you may opt out of certain sharing of information used for advertising purposes. Learn more about your advertising choices [here](http://www.aboutads.info/). You may also have the ability to disable specific Winamp features that share information, as described in more detail below.

#### Privacy Information for Specific Winamp Services

Winamp offers many products and services that collect or use your Winamp Information for personalization or other purposes. All of our Services comply with this Privacy Policy, but some have additional data collection practices that you should know about:

Winamp Player

To enhance your playback experience, the Winamp Player uses technology powered by AMG and/or Gracenote to provide information about the song or other media you are listening to, such as album art, artist biography, discography, and purchase information. If you use the Infoviewer and Now Playing features, information regarding the specific media you are listening to may be collected and stored in a manner that does not identify you personally. Winamp, AMG, and Gracenote may use this information to identify top songs and artists being requested by our users or for other purposes. You have the option to turn this feature off by not accessing the Now Playing view and pressing the "Hide Info" button within the Library views.

The Winamp player automatically gathers certain usage information from you, which may include the length of your session, the number of tracks and streams you've played in a certain session, the number of CDs you've burned, played or ripped, the number of tracks you've transferred to a portable device, the number of playlists you've created, the number of plug-ins you've installed, and the number of skins you've installed. Winamp uses this information to better understand how people use the various parts of our service and to improve the content, features, and functionality of the player. You have choices on whether to share certain usage information with Winamp. The Winamp Preferences screen offers you the ability to opt-in or opt-out of reporting these usage statistics.

Winamp Orgler

The Winamp Orgler is an optional feature that enables you to share your playback information with other Winamp and AOL users. If enabled, the Winamp Orgler collects your playback information, which may include artist, album, title, track number, time zone, location, AOL Screen Name or user name, and other related listening information and posts it online allowing you to see your history and enabling you to share this information with other Orgler and AOL users. This optional feature is turned "off" by default, and your playback information will not be collected or stored unless you decide to enable it.

Gracenote Playlist

The Gracenote Playlist feature builds customized playlists for you by analyzing the music in your library. It works by identifying other tracks that are similar to a song or songs you select. To build custom playlists, the software sends information to Gracenote's databases, including song title, artist name, album name, track number, genre, and song duration. No information that identifies you personally is sent or shared with Gracenote. If you do not wish to share this information, do not use the Gracenote Playlist feature, or you may uninstall the Nullsoft Playlist Generator Plug-in from the Winamp software under the preferences menu.

Gracenote Auto-Tag

The Auto-Tag feature of Winamp, also powered by Gracenote, gives you the option to update information related to the song you are listening to with the information provided from the Gracenote database. If you do not wish to have Gracenote receive this information, do not use the Auto-Tag feature, or you may uninstall the Nullsoft Auto-Tagger Plug-in from the Winamp software under the Preferences menu.

Skins

Winamp offers you the ability to create and post skins for others to review and download. If you decide to create a skin to share with others, Winamp will show your AOL Screen Name or username and provide a link so that others can provide you feedback about the skin. 

Winamp also gives you the option to write a review of a skin. The review will appear on the Winamp website with the skin and will contain your AOL Screen Name or username. Winamp automatically keeps track of the number of times a skin has been downloaded. 

Some of our advertising partners may create skins that contain web beacons. These web beacons provide the advertiser with information about the use of the skin, such as the number of times a user clicked on the advertiser's logo.

#### Cookies, Web Beacons, and Similar Technologies

Winamp may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies in combination with your Winamp information to enhance and personalize your experience on Winamp, including to operate and improve offerings through Winamp; to help authenticate you; to remember your preferences and registration information; to enable a shopping cart; to present and help measure and research the effectiveness of Winamp offerings, advertisements, and e-mail communications (by determining which Winamp e-mails you open and act upon); and to customize the content and advertisements provided to you through Winamp. You can control cookies through your browser's settings; however, if you reject all cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of certain Winamp offerings.

Winamp and its advertisers may also use ad network providers to help present advertisements on the Winamp Services. These ad network providers use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies on your computer to help present, better target, and measure the effectiveness of their advertisements, using data gathered over time and across their networks of sites to determine or predict the characteristics and preferences of their audience. Winamp may share certain non-personally identifiable information about you as a user (such as user age and zip code) with certain ad network providers to help them deliver more relevant advertisements through their ad networks. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by ad network providers is subject to their own privacy policies, not Winamp's. You can find out more about ad network providers and the choices you have about these technologies by clicking [here](http://about.aol.com/aolnetwork/beacons).

#### Protecting Children

Winamp is intended for a general audience and is not designed for children under age 13.

#### Security

Winamp has established safeguards to help prevent unauthorized access to or misuse of your Winamp Information, but cannot guarantee that your Winamp Information will never be disclosed in a manner inconsistent with this Privacy Policy (for example, as a result of unauthorized acts by third parties that violate applicable law or the policies of Winamp and its affiliated providers). To protect your privacy and security, Winamp uses passwords to help verify your identity before granting access or making corrections to any of your Winamp Information. Please help us by keeping your username or password private and secure.

#### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns about the Winamp Privacy Policy or its implementation, you may contact us by clicking [here](mailto:support@winamp.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Inquiry) to send an email. Please be sure to include "Privacy Policy Inquiry" within the subject line.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Winamp may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, and so you should review this Policy periodically. If there are significant changes to Winamp's information practices, we will post a notice on our website and provide appropriate choices before using the Winamp Information we have already collected in a new or inconsistent way. You may be provided other privacy-related information in connection with your use of Services from Winamp, as well as for special features and services not described in this Policy that may be introduced in the future.

In the event that ownership of Winamp was to change as a result of a merger, acquisition or transfer to another company, your Winamp Information may be transferred. If such a transfer results in a material change in the use of your Winamp information, Winamp will provide notice about the choices you have to decline to permit such a transfer.

This policy is effective June 30, 2009.
